When a permission that has been granted on
a resource is no longer needed, it should
be revoked.
People who have permission on a resource when
that permission is not needed are a risk for
doing something harmful to data, such as accidentally
updating or deleting data or worse, performing
malicious acts on data.
The REVOKE statement revokes permissions on
an object.
I have the GRANT statement up that we used
in the previous video to give the procTester
account execute privileges on the GetDepartment
stored procedure.
The REVOKE statement is similar to the GRANT
statement.
I will just replace the word GRANT with REVOKE,
replace WITH GRANT OPTION with CASCADE as
that is needed to eliminate the grant option,
and run this statement.
We see the message that the command completed
successfully and the permission has been revoked
from this account.